Guide to the Christabel Forsyth Fiske Papers, circa 1941-1943
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Christabel Forsyth Fiske Papers
circa 1941-1943
Fiske, Christabel Forsyth, 1869-1956
0.4 cubic feet (1 box)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
The collection contains drafts of a manuscript by Christabel Fiske entitled Robert Burton's Imagery: Three Essays. Also included is an essay on Henry James's The Golden Bowl and a letter to a potential publisher.
Biographical Note
When Christabel Fiske (1869-1956) died, former colleague Helen Lockwood praised her as "one of Vassar's great women." From 1903 to 1940, Fiske taught English at Vassar, a career for which she prepared at Cornell and Columbia University (now George Washington University). She had a wide range of literary interests, including English and German medieval literature, John Milton, and the study of language. Known as a stimulating teacher who took great pains to develop each student's abilities, Miss Fiske was reputed to dismiss classes when she found the students were unprepared. She was the editor of Vassar Medieval Studies and, for fourteen years, the Vassar Journal of Undergraduate Studies.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains drafts of a manuscript by Christabel Fiske entitled Robert Burton's Imagery: Three Essays. Also included is an essay on Henry James's The Golden Bowl and a letter to a potential publisher.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
Burton, Robert, 1577-1640
Organizations:
Vassar College--Faculty
Subjects:
Women college teachers
VCL Categories:
Literature and Writing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, February 2007. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, March 2023.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Christabel Fiske.
Container List
- Letter from Christabel Fiske to The Kenyon Review, 1943 (Folder 1)
- "Reminiscent Imagery in The Golden Bowl," draft, undated (Folder 2)
- Robert Burton's Imagery: Three Essays, title page drafts, circa 1941 (Folder 3)
- "Burton's Imagery: Its Structural Significance"
  - Draft #1, partial, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 4)
  - Draft #2, partial, annotated, circa 1941 (Folder 5)
  - Draft #3, partial, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 6)
- "A 'Frontispiece' Expounded: Burton's Literary Criticism-in-Imagery"
  - Draft #1, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 7)
  - Draft #2, partial, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 8)
  - Draft #3, partial, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 9)
  - Draft #4, partial, circa 1941 (Folder 10)
  - Draft #5, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 11)
  - Draft #6, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 12)
  - Draft #7, partial, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 13)
  - Draft #8, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 14)
  - Draft #9, partial, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 15)
  - Draft #10, partial, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 16)
- "Robert Burton's Mansion of Criticism: Its Symbolic Relationships"
  - "The Mansion of Criticism," draft #1, circa 1941 (Folder 17)
  - "The Mansion of Criticism," draft #2, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 18)
  - Draft #3, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 19)
  - Draft #4, partial, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 20)
  - Draft #5, partial, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 21)
  - Draft #6, partial, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 22)
  - Draft #7, partial, corrected, circa 1941 (Folder 23)